Guide to the Papers of Philos Cooke and Louise Stevens Cooke, 1907-1936
Department of Special Collections
Papers of Philos Cooke and Louise Stevens Cooke,
1907-1936
Special Collections M0144
Cooke, Philos
.5 linear ft.(4 folders)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Philos Cooke, 1936
Scope and Content
Summary: Letters, postcards, pamphlets, and typescript biography. Includes correspondence of Fanny Chapman on Tahiti, material on Arizona's Constitutinal Convention, typescript biography of Louise
Stevens Cooke, material on Pitcairn Island, letter from Fred Christian, and writings by Theo Haultain about aborigines.
Container List
- Chapman - Cooke correspondence (Tahiti) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. 1935 Sept. 20ans Frank Philos Cooke. Explanation & background of Tahitian letters.
  - 2. n.d.Postcard of Tiare Hotel
  - 3. 1907, Apr. 30.A.L.S. & cvr. 0. Salmon to Louise Stevens. Prices for guiding tourists.
  - 4. 1925, Jan. 11.A.L.S. Fanny Chapman to Louise Cooke. Personal, flu epidemic
  - 5. 1925, Dec. 13.A.L.S. Fanny Chapman to Louise Cooke
  - 6. 1926, June 27.A.L.S Fanny Chapman to Louise Cooke
  - 7. 1926, Sept. 17A.L.S. Fanny Chapman to Louise Cooke. Personal
  - 8. 1926, Sept. 19.A.L.S. Fanny Chapman to Louise Cooke
  - 9. 1927, Sept. 12.A.L.S.Fanny Chapman to Louise Cooke
  - 10. 1927, Sept. 12.ALS Fanny Chapman to Louise Cooke. Personal, leprosy.
  - 11. 1927, Sept. 12.T.L.S. Scudder Mersman to Philos Cooke re: the Chapmans
  - 12. 1927, Dec. 11.als Fanny Chapman to Louise Cooke
  - 13. 1931, June 22.als Fanny Chapman to Philos Cooke. Death of Louise and Ben (in 1930)
- Arizona Material (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1. 1935. Dec. 15.tls James H. Kerby to Philos Cooke with ptd. "Minutes of the Constitutional Convention of the Territory of Arizona" & comment by Cooke
  - 2. 1936, Feb. 12."Louise Stevens Cooke, An American Woman, A story of some Re-incarnations in circumstances." Short typescript biography by Philos Cooke
- Pitcairn Island (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1. 1935, Jan 5.A.L.S Mr. & Mrs. E.R. McCandlish to Philos Cooke
  - 2. 1936, Jan. 6T.L. Philos Cooke to Fred M. Christian
  - 3. 1936, Feb. 11.A.L.S. Fred M. Christian to Philos Cooke
  - 4. n.d.Envelope with sewing machine needle
- Haultain, Theo (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1. Writings about aborigines; their culture - beliefs, legends, etc. a) "The Black Samaritan" b) "The Oldest Land"